[music]
Back in November, we hosted the first
ever in-person AI native DevCon [music]
in New York. This June 1st and 2nd,
we're bringing it to London. It's two
days built for AI Native developers and
[music] engineering teams. One day full
of hands-on workshops, and one day full
of practical talks on agent skills,
[music] context engineering, agent
orchestration and enablement platforms,
and how teams are actually shipping AI
in production. Join us at the Brewery in
London near the Barbacan for all of
that, plus [music] networking, parties,
giveaways, and a room full of people
building the future of AI native
development. You can also join us from
anywhere in the world via the live
stream. As you're listening to this
podcast, you get 30% off your ticket
with code pod30. Just head to a [music]
nativedevcon.io and we'll see you in
London.
Hello and welcome to a milestone episode
of the AI native dev. My name is Simon
Maple, one of the hosts of this show.
And joining me is
>> Guy Pajari. I'm the co-host, Simon's
co-host and sidekick overall.
And uh today's a milestone episode
because do you know guy we've uh already
done already shot and and released 100
episodes of the AI native dev.
>> That's insane.
>> How does that feel?
>> Like I don't know how we get anything
else done.
>> I know. Just sort of all the time just
sort of coming here and talking to
interesting people which actually is not
a bad reality.
>> Yeah. We're so we're a podcast company,
right? And we and we we do this other
thing on the side.
>> It's the fallback. It's the safety net.
I don't know how safe it is but
[laughter]
>> it is interesting.
>> Amazing. And so this episode is really
going to look back at the previous 100
episodes and we're going to take sound
bites uh from some of the most amazing
speakers that like you say we've had uh
on the on the show.
>> So it's going to be about 45 hours this
uh
>> something around then. Yeah, it it'll
definitely be a week at least. Um so so
yeah, make sure you you've got a long
drive or [laughter]
and we're going to we're going to add
our commentary um and also see how
things have changed. for example, let's
run the first clip, guys, because I
think we're going to find this very,
very interesting.
>> Okay,
>> if anyone who's predicting what that
looks like in a year or two is going to
be fundamentally wrong. And I think that
that's really what makes that so
exciting. We don't know where we're
going other than that we do know that
we're going to keep building software
while maintaining, you know, billions,
if not trillions of lines of code that
are already out there. Thomas Donker of
course the uh the previous CEO of GitHub
and now I believe founder of a new
company new startup in in the AI space
called entire. So if anyone's going to
be fundamentally wrong about a
prediction in one to two years let's go
back maybe let's say one to two years
guy to episode one where you predicted
something around AI development.
>> Yeah I never claimed to be too wise. No,
no, no, no, no, no. Caveats now, guy.
Let's hear what you have to say and then
we'll see how accurate you were.
>> I think the biggest change that we
should expect that I feel I feel fairly
convinced will happen is the move from
codeentric to specentric development.
Um, when you think about how you develop
software today, uh, you write you get
some requirements, you write some code,
you make 100 decisions in that code that
never leave the code. Uh, and the code
very quickly becomes the source of
truth. uh and we focus on evolving it
and growing it. I think in the world of
AI native development, we will have a
means of specifying what it is that we
need and AI will provide the
implementation.
>> So guy tell us uh tell us your new take
how how accurate were you? Yeah, I mean
I think so so something's spot on uh
some aspect of it in that uh I think I
think today it's a much less
controversial statement to say that you
know code will become disposable and
that uh implementations uh will will be
you know something that is just kind of
created for it uh and so that you will
revolve around around intent you know
around what it is that you want to
build. Um so I think it was like not far
off on that
>> bit that bit was good. Tell me about the
bit that's fundamentally wrong. As
Thomas would say,
>> I think the the the primary kind of
change I'd like to think evolution kind
of in in my thinking, our thinking here
at Tessle, uh is this move from spec to
context, right? It's when when we
recorded that episode and we're you know
talking about specentric software uh we
talked about how you want to make sure
that LLMs this is pre-agents you know
now agents will uh make sure to update
to kind of capture you will you will
convey what it is that you want to build
and then the LLMs will build that and
they will fill in the gaps that's what
we talked about back then and while that
is not wrong you know it's it's true LLM
need to do that it's just such a small
part of development when you think about
your dev team and what do you expect of
them you
You don't really say, "Hey, make sure
that every time you follow you read this
doc and you follow the exact
instructions and you update that." You
know, sometimes you want them to do
that, but generally you want them to to
make good decisions, you know, including
choosing when to update documents and
read them.
>> But that's just like a portion of what
you want from a great developer in your
team. you know, you want them to uh to,
you know, have all sorts of preferences
around how they build and how do they
collaborate on it and how do they test
and make sure it didn't break and how do
they balance kind of quality and how do
they and then sort of speed and how do
they kind of use your existing
infrastructure and how do they
troubleshoot issues and so all of that
is really about training the developer
and so I guess my my kind of catchphrase
today is to think that uh we've moved
from specking the program to specking
the programmer so it's much more about
how do you want a developer a great
developer in your team to behave and and
again there's a portion like I don't
think specentric software or specdriven
development as is the kind of the term
today goes away like I think that is
important I just think it is a subset of
how you want today agents to build and
it's more important when you think about
the new software development it should
revolve around um training these uh AI
agents to build the way you want them to
build
>> such a Such a good way of putting it.
And the way one one way that resonates
with me is is onboarding. And it's like
if you was to hire an individual to work
on your team, you would spend time
onboarding them, training them. They
they could be the most senior developer
on your team like that you've hired, but
they still need to know how your team
works, your organization works, and take
on those those policies, ways of working
to actually use their skills in the new
environment. And there's no reason why
we shouldn't do that with an agent as
well. And it's that onboarding of that
agent and very very very nice.
>> Yeah, absolutely. And that would sort of
adds it's like onboarding and then
continual training. No, you want to make
sure that they you know as as a group
you learn things. So some of it is you
individually learn but a lot of it is
the the group learns you know the team
learns and you want to make sure you
accumulate that and retrain the team. So
both those are human analogies, right?
About how do you want uh people in the
team to to work? You want them to on
board and then you want them to kind of
keep keep with it and then sort of adapt
and evolve and be aligned with the rest
of the organization how they build. So
we need to build that. So all of that
today manifests in the form of context
engineering. Uh and I guess the unit of
software today or unit of context today
that is most discussed is skills. And so
I'd say if you take the clip, you can
swap the word spec for skill and you
know it will still be natural language
words. It will still be uh a capture of
intent. Uh but it is not a program spec.
It is a programming spec. You know how
do you how do you want to develop
software here?
>> So it was a it was quite a subtle thing
that you were fundamentally wrong about.
>> I was fundamentally wrong. I had to be
fundamentally wrong about something
otherwise we wouldn't be learning
anything. Would be boring.
>> Simon I mean we can agree you and I can
agree that you were fundamentally wrong
about that. So that that's fine. Okay.
Next up, you know, Thomas didn't just
mention that you were fundament
fundamentally wrong about something. He
also talked about the changes that
developers uh need to go through. Let's
uh let's hear from Thomas.
>> Simon Wilson on his on his blog recently
had like a statement. I'm paraphrasing
um but this was like we have to get
comfortable with not reviewing every
single line of code before we deploy
them into production because the sheer
amount of code that a single agent can
write 247 now you paralyze that into
running 10 agents in parallel all the
time. you're just never going to be able
to review all the code without the one
human doing that becoming the ma major
bottleneck and effectively erasing some
of the productivity gains from this
agent.
>> Yeah, very interesting take there from
from Thomas and actually also supported
by a couple of other folks on the on the
podcast. Uh Peter Guagenti from episode
three way back uh also talked about a
potential future whereby uh agents might
actually write code that isn't even
human readable. So maybe something close
to a bite code or or a machine style
code. Uh Bea also from Thoughtworks in
episode 69 also said she ran into
situations where she actually has done
so much almost like a vibe coding but
you know allowing the agent to to write
that code that she feels so disconnected
from the code. She isn't necessarily the
most appropriate person to do the code
reviews. What's your take on this?
>> Yeah, I think uh so super interesting
fully aligned you know with sort of the
Thomas' view in general like that the
human is the bottleneck. And uh there
was like all sorts of similar statements
in the AI world. You had sort of Elon
Musk talk about how he had some weird
spreadsheet analogy on it, but he was
saying if you have like a gazillion
spreadsheets on it and just a few cells
need to be filled in by humans, you've
reduced it down to human speed. uh uh
and I think that's what we're sort of
seeing with code review uh that you know
if humans are the bottleneck then you
know you get human traits like review
fatigue but then you also just sort of
see slowness right this is the the human
speed you know is limiting uh how much
how much can AI kind of code and build
up and so you're just moving the bottom
neck I think this will actually extend
further so once you get through and you
deploy now the problem will be that the
system changes too quickly and we can't
uh do uh like uh observability and root
cause analysis and handle those. We
can't figure out that a bug needs to
come back and uh and be resolved and
then resolve that and deploy the fix. So
really throughout the end to end
software development life cycle, our
aspiration really has to be and I think
we're seeing this in the advanced
organizations to really identify every
single step of that process. Um and I
think that is the only way to to move
forward. uh and when we think about okay
but but these things are unreliable
right they don't do you know that they
build uh your the right thing is it it
comes back to context right and uh you
know at Tesla we talk about the the
context development life cycle right and
I think agents should operate the SDLC
and the human should live in the context
development life cycle in the CDLC they
should really be a guide and I think
that the human analogy is really a
manager and if you're you know at the
moment we're like the frontline manager
with the player coach you know you're
you're sort of giving the tasks you're
monitoring and you're you know getting
things done and increasingly if you want
to increase your scale and have more
employees in this case AI employees or
sort of you know AI labor that is
getting things done then then you need
to become you know a second line manager
and a third line manager and I think
those are those really predicate on your
ability to define what correct looks
like to convey instructions to uh to
identify that mistakes were were made
and be able to resolve them and so you
need to move up the stack and the way
you communicate with agents is through
context. It's not just context, it's
context is the tools you make available
to them. It is the um the like the the
foundation to be able to observe what
has happened. And so that's why when we
think about context development life
cycle, we think about kind of generating
some piece of context like it it's
actually we talked about that in one of
those episodes as well about how you
know knowing what you want is actually
hard and so like figure out what it is
that you want, what is good, what is
correct behavior and then you want to be
able to test and evaluate. This is maybe
the equivalent of testing humans but in
a little bit more software of like your
tests to know whether these instructions
are well adhered to. So we think about
eval. You want to be able to disseminate
and communicate to that to the uh horde
of agents you know that you have the
right communication to the right agent
at the right time and then you want to
observe what has happened and once
you've observed you will have learned a
bunch of things also a bunch of like
facts in the world have changed know
maybe some codes uh have has changed
maybe a pricing model a new model came
out and so you want to learn from that
come back and sort of update your
instructions and so all of that is what
we think of as the context development
life cycle so I think that is that is
very kind of aligned uh with this
destination and I think what we've it's
interesting that the world of AI uh you
know I I I I like my crystal ball you
know like I like these you know
fundamentally wrong uh predictions uh
but uh and and and looking ahead but I
think one of the things that I find most
interesting about the way AI has evolved
is uh it's oftentimes around solve the
next problem solve the next problem
solve the next problem so I think the
next problem to solve right now is code
review because we're filling it there I
think subsequently we'll get into those
deployment uh threats Because one of the
biggest worries is of course the
quickest, cheapest, shortterm fix is
just to allow things to happen and for
developers to go if I'm the bottleneck,
I can just eliminate myself from being
the bottleneck by just either just
checking, yeah, this is fine or just not
doing it at all.
>> So it's about doing things. How can we
speed things up, continue at the pace
that AI wants to generate at
>> while doing things accurately and
properly and adding that context in to
almost take take things away from the
developer so the developer the human can
really look at the things that are most
important rather than as code changes
scale up to try and do things faster by
you know
>> by learning how to code review faster
that doesn't make sense. But adding this
context actually can take a lot of that
away from us and for us to be that
second line manager to understand it to
to to manage it makes it a lot more
sense.
>> Yeah. And I think the cloud analogy kind
of works pretty well here which is you
know when we were in waterfall era a lot
of these processes and a lot of these
reviews were human and as we moved into
cloud we had to automate them right we
had to define
>> to do policy as code as the sort of the
meta name for it but you know
infrastructure as code to deploy your
infrastructure automated testing you
know and dev QA became a thing it wasn't
a thing before on it and so we we
actually have have gone through a fairly
similar uh shift in when we moved to
clouds to say things are moving faster
the bottleneck is the human let's
automate this action of the human and
now we're we're doing another another
leap over there and it was mighty
uncomfortable at the time to say oh what
you mean I I'll automate this and I will
deploy it and I will deploy more bugs
>> and you know the time has shown that if
you close the loop then yes you might
even deploy more bugs but because you're
able to identify those and then fix them
and then come back and roll those out
the systems that were continuously
deploying doing, you know, today's well
known. They are more secure. They are
they have higher quality, you know, they
have all of those, but you have to go
end to end. If all you've done is remove
the gates, right, and just said just
just let it let it flow, then you end up
with a system that is more broken. Uh so
a lot of that cloud learning actually
applies here substantially and and uh
you have to think about the end to end
uh uh operation. It it is happening
faster than in cloud. And so what we
don't have is the benefit of uh of like
trying it out and seeing if it works. I
have one more small comment just on on
what you said about uh non-readable code
which is interestingly something that is
now starting to surface as a safety
concern. Mhm.
>> Uh so there's there's actually some
significant call outs to say that
actually a safety requirement should be
that LLMs are not allowed to produce
things that are not human reviewable
>> uh like binary code or you know their
own languages even if it is more
efficient for safety uh as part of being
able to supervise agents. So that's
interesting. I don't know if it's an
over kind of an exaggerated concern or
not. uh but I think right now more
likely you know in the prediction realm
that we will uh produce readable output
readable code and then it'll get
compiled.
>> So following on from code review I guess
next up we have uh Annie Vela who's a
distinguished engineer from Westpacking
and um really interesting blog and
discussion that I had with her around
the future of developers. Let's hear
from Annie.
There are literally people who enjoy
going through those sorts of elite
coding exercises on there's a reason
that website exists, right? There's
leaderboards of people who can solve the
most complex problems the fastest. So
that I don't think will be very
important anymore. That's a skill that a
lot of software engineers have taken to
be the core of being a really strong
software engineer. That is a skill I
think we're going to need to learn to
let go of both in interviews and
personally. It just it won't make much
sense anymore. Why would you need to be
an expert at writing that level of code
when an AI can probably generate
something good enough for you?
>> Really important point and I think it's
something that I think we're most I
think most of the industry is aligned on
it, but it's possibly one of the things
that we are least comfortable giving
away because it's a thing that we enjoy.
Yeah. Uh it's a thing that we have
become it's it's part of what excellence
is in or or seen as in development in
programming to write the nicest code the
cleanest code that solves the deepest
most complex problems
>> and be fast about it
>> and be fast about it. Is this going to
be a problem for developers adapting
>> uh in the future? I mean I think for
some for sure it I I like the mental
model that says like some developers I'm
generalizing here but like some
developers are more motivated by the
craft of coding
>> while others are more motivated by the
impact right or by the creation. uh and
so I think if you're motivated by the
creation side then you know agents are
amazing you can produce so much the
shortening that journey from idea to ex
execution even if you were are very very
fast as a human developer it still takes
you that time and while in the meantime
you could have thought of other things
right
>> it's the means to the end of the coding
versus
so so the fun is uh having an idea and
bringing it to life and tuning it and
orienting it and even making some
architectural decisions and things like
that right around what is elegant and
what's not but like writing the code uh
step in the journey right is not the
goal while for others writing the code
is the craft you know and I I do think
there's beauty in the architecture of
you know like writing correct code you
know well-crafted short simple code on
it all of those are
>> good abstracted Java classes and
interfaces
>> exactly yeah and also in like modern
languages but uh but uh you know you you
um so so there's there's beauty in it
you know so there is there's probably
room for it from an aesthetic
perspective and a skill, but it it's
slightly becoming like a a factory
manufactured furniture versus kind of
handcrafted ones, right? You can create
things that are that are very local.
They might even be able to better
represent very very specific
preferences, very specific decisions
that are almost hard to convey in any
way that isn't code. But for the vast
vast majority of furniture, you're
totally comfortable with them being
factory-made, right? With them being u
built by machines. Uh and and so I think
that is true for code as well and for
increasingly sophisticated and
complicated code. And the advantage of
doing it by hand is is so minuscule
compared to the advantage of being able
to produce it quickly, cheaply by more
people. Like think about the the loss of
knowledge when you have one person with
the idea and they need to convey that to
you know a person to convey that to a
person you know to eventually get to
someone who writes the code. So
>> dropping some of these middlemen. Um so
all of those are just so much more
valuable. So the reality is I think
there will be room for handcrafted code
in some niches in some very specific
spots and some artistal element and I
think it can remain a hobby just like
today. There's a bunch of these, you
know, hobbyist hardware, hobbyist, like
it's okay for that to to happen. But I
think as a profession, you got to let
go.
>> So, so do you think first of all the de
the best developers five years ago will
continue to be the best developers in
five years? What do you think the the
the key skills need to be for a
successful developer?
>> It's a good question. I don't know what
the sort of the percentage is of people
that are more the best developers
because of their ability to craft code
versus the best developers otherwise.
I'd say that even like throughout the
years, the best developers are the ones
that truly understood the problem to be
solved and the architectural tradeoffs
to be made. And then they they just saw
the codew writing as a uh as a pass
through, right? they knew how to then
translate the English into code quickly.
Um, and so I think it's the same best
developers, but I think there's uh um if
you were to contrast or like compare,
you know, different developers, for some
of them, the strength of code writing uh
is was a a bigger part of that mix. Uh
and that will diminish. I do there's
another element of just speed of
decision-m and so writing code is slow
and because it is slow you actually get
to think about the problem and these
architectural decisions and all of those
as you as you code
>> and I think that is an interesting thing
that is lost a little bit when you are
coding quickly because you need to
decide more things up front
>> and and that's hard because sometimes
you don't need to do it uh I see the
pattern that uh that is emerging to to
try and tackle that is okay as you get
the agent to code be explicit around
architecture. Even if it's not you who
made the decision but the agent have the
agent be explicit about the architecture
review that don't be afraid to tell the
agent scrap all of that and build again.
So this ability to rebuild
>> uh is is really more important than the
ability to build. How do you capture
that? Slightly comes back to context of
you know in this case maybe it is
sometimes specs and architecture is a
specific type of context to say this is
what we've built. This is these are the
emphasis points about how we built it.
Now remove the whole thing and write it
in you know I don't know Java or again
rust something
>> uh per your requirements
>> and I love that I love that thought
where you know as coding becomes
something that's very fast and actually
taken away from us slightly we do lose
that time to think as we're building but
what we do gain is that that faster
iteration which allows us to gain
feedback faster and throw away quicker.
Yeah,
>> we can throw away we can and we can use
that feedback to build something faster
with real, you know, stronger knowledge
about what works and what doesn't.
>> Precisely. Which which by the way, like
the a recent episode with Chad Fowler
about regenerative software and the
Phoenix architecture is really all about
that.
>> Amazing. So, next up, let's jump into
the world of from dev to ops via DevOps.
uh alka
>> you might hire the world's best s sur
who knows terraform and cloud inside and
out but when they join your organization
they don't know anything about your
organization so they don't know do you
run windows in production rail in
production Ubuntu in production now they
might be power users at all of those
things but the context of knowing hey as
an organization we standardized on rail
that's critical piece of context that
you have to be a useful sority at the or
right you don't want to hire someone the
rest of my stack is windows and all of a
sudden this person's writing Linux for
me but doesn't help me right they need
to understand how does the organization
work what have we standardized on what
does my existing infrastructure look
like for them to generate things that
are then contextually relevant to my
environment
>> and you can tell from your from your
youthful looks there guy that was that
was back in episode 19 uh Arman of
course the co-founder of Hashorp um so
yeah context is the difference between
great AI and useless AI and it's not
just development it's generally AI right
>> in ops I think what we're seeing in
first of all context is probably the
most abused word right now it's like
anything you need to know you know and I
think the the meta perspective over
there is to separate intelligence from
knowledge you can be massively
intelligent but what do you know and and
I think there's a bunch of things you
need to know to operate in an or uh I I
really liked the the episode with Armon
which was you know early in in in DevOps
we also had a recent one with uh Mirao
who's the founder of D-Zero kind of a
modern observability play also talking
about context and how it's important
from an observability uh perspective and
the ability to troubleshoot and do root
cause analysis. Also in the world of
DevOps also highlighting the the key is
context. I I think uh ops is an
interesting place because when you think
about who in your team like which
developers are you know carrying the
pager and able to troubleshoot the
things or even like the superhero sRes
in uh in some organizations who are the
ones that will decult to firefight you
know a really bad uh production outage
those people they have a very broad
understanding of the system right they
they know what are the types of
applications what are the patterns that
are deployed what is the infrastructure
that they are running on So you know all
the way from like operating system to
the types of scaling historical like
recent uh or past outages like known
weaknesses within the infrastructure
that have not yet been prioritized. You
know there's there's all this knowledge
and because of all that knowledge they
can look at a piece of of of current
data of like this system crashed or that
you know those requests are slow or
whatever it is. uh and they're able to
kind of quickly translate that into oh
it's probably this problem and it's
therefore probably this solution uh and
so I think it is very uh uh like context
is very very important because often
times the the production system is where
it all comes together right it is the
infrastructure you've deployed it is the
system that you are connected to it is
of course your code and your application
>> and what you're seeing in in so so
definitely seeing in the world of devops
that context is important important than
any any player kind of on the on the
planet will will talk about uh about
context uh when when it comes to DevOps
and what we're seeing is uh root cause
analysis capability is the one that is
manifesting as the as probably the most
useful in the DevOps world to be able to
look at these kind of vast amounts of
data that exist about how your system
operates which is a strength of AI and
agents uh to understand it combine that
with context in the organization where
you're not just blindly looking at the
logs, but you don't know anything else.
You're you're actually able to to gather
more of that information and then you go
off to uh to understand it. And the
advantage of root cause analysis is that
it's it's kind of harmless. um where
you're actually seeing still very
cautious use of AI which was still the
case like back in you know uh in episode
19 you know with uh with Armon uh is the
use of it for actual ops uh activity
like people are still very uncomfortable
with an agent deploying a system
slightly slightly more comfortable with
writing you know some Terraform code
>> that's another interesting piece because
like everything that you talked about up
until the Terraform code uh is is really
pulling sensitive information I guess
but information that has come out of
your ops infrastructure whether it's
troubleshooting pulling data and logs
and things like that but when we talk
about creating the creation of Terraform
code uh enterprise terraform code that's
not just something that you find on
someone's GitHub account right whereas
typically there is so much more you know
for a developer there's tons of code
that that that you know is that the
agent can train on uh the LLM can train
on it and will provide you with good
suggestions and good alternatives to
what you're trying to do. But is there
really the the the right training data
there for an agent to use or an LM to
use when generating enterprise quality
and enterprisegrade uh Terraform scripts
for example?
>> Yeah, I think I think there was
definitely a hold back in the early
days. There's still a decent amount uh
out there. you know there's a bunch of
public modules and things like that and
you know there's there's good
documentation for it so it can follow it
and eventually you know declarative
languages like HCL the hashorp language
or or rego and such are a little bit
easier there's still probably behind the
like a lot of commentary aboutgo the
open policy agent you know not being you
know agents not being great at creating
it so there's probably room to improve I
I I I do I have seen substantial
improvements on it or like hear you know
from from uh various users and you you
see it probably for two primary reasons
One is there's some data aggregation
that happens just as as these things are
actually used in in the real world and
so there's more data accumulated from
private sources. Uh not all of it can be
trained right away but still there's
signals that can be learned. And the
second is the ability to create
synthetic data and so the labs are
increasingly relying not just on public
data but on synthetic data and I do
think that infrastructures code has the
same kind of attribute that regular code
has and sometimes even more which is you
can generate something and you can check
if it actually works. So you can deploy
it and sort of see whether the result is
correct or not. Uh so that becomes just
a kind of a data generation exercise.
>> But still that is one kind of limiting
factor is indeed the sort of the public
private and maybe the the price of
generating it. Another big uh concern or
like limitation is the ability to deal
with time series data and so when you
analyze observability data it's very
important the sequence you know of
things that that happen. And the NLMs
are like a little bit more kind of meta
uh uh thinkers, you know, of how it is.
And you've seen a variety. We had Ollie
from Data Dog on the podcast on it. You
know, we talked about Toto, their uh
little dog, but also their sort of time
series uh model. And you see some of the
startups like traceable uh in the space
and all that actually look to create
models or or at least fine-tune kind of
RL models around that. And so the
ability to deal with those volumes and
then on top of all of those there's just
like sheer price like when you're
producing a lot of data you're not going
to you're going to flow that through
opus and you'll be happy you know until
it hits your bank account like it's not
uh uh so you you need to be smarter and
you know there's much many more attempts
of sort of using open and cheap models.
So I'd say overall context is key in
DevOps as much as it is anywhere else
and maybe even more so. Um, and I still
think the DevOps world, and we've had
in, you know, like we've mentioned three
episodes over here, we've had a few
other references to it, still ends up
being a little bit more cautious, mostly
because of some of these sort of
technical limitations. But I'd also say
the blast radius of, you know, if they
got it wrong, you know, I guess what
what are the horror scenarios that we
sort of hear about agents running
systems is they drop the database in
production, right? They those are are
kind of very hard to recover from uh
type setups. So, it's an interesting
let's solve code review. and [laughter]
then you know kind of evolve from there.
Uh but it's still it's still making
progress.
>> You mentioned meta thinkers.
Let's switch. This is so seamless guy
Ian Thomas who's a meta thinker because
he he works for Meta. Um he he he has
some thoughts about the adoption of AI
within the Meta organization and I
caught up with him at uh at Cucon AI in
in New York. And um actually to set this
up, Peter uh Guanti who who's at mine
also mentioned a stat that he gave was
uh that Gartner uh say that 10% of
enterprise devs use AI tools today but
by 2027
that number hits 80%. Let's see what Ian
thinks about that.
>> We had a few people that were really
keen and and sort of experimenting and
they were they were finding value of
these tools outside of work. And then we
had a bunch of really senior engineers
who were perhaps a little bit more
skeptical. And then gradually over time,
we've seen adoption grow. Last time I
checked, we were over 80% week active
users.
>> Oh wow.
>> 80% over 80% weekly active users within
meta, which okay, is a little bit biased
perhaps uh given how deeply involved
they are with AI, but over 80% weekly
active users within meta using AI dev
tools today. Does that surprise you?
um it it doesn't but I feel like I have
a few grains of salt to kind of throw
into that statement you know uh one is
this is this is a world of of kind of
halves and have nots you know on it and
what you're seeing is this sort of big
polarity between organizations that have
embraced and invested and you know have
uh leadership that is both bought in and
able to execute on it and you know
driven and sort of businesses that are
in a state to push the use of agents on
it which is often times times, you know,
disruptive, expensive, you know, it's
it's like it's not an easy thing to
doing it. And and so those organizations
are are ahead. And we're seeing a lot of
other organizations, you know, and we
engaged with a lot of them here in which
you'd sort of say this organization uses
agents,
>> but really when you pierce through and
we talked to a lot of these orgs,
there's like a cohort of forerunners
that they are uh embracing agents and
some of them are actually very
sophisticated in how they use it. But
then the vast majority of the
organization is still very nent you know
everybody's using code completion and
and the likes. So anyways that's so
that's one is like I think there's a
difference between the sort of the 10%
stat which is also about a year earlier.
Oh yes
>> but uh between that stat and the 80%
stat just between organizations and meta
is still a very AI forward it is a large
organization but it is an AI forward
very driven very technology
organization.
The second thing is I think we don't yet
have good enough metrics to say what
does it mean that you're using agents uh
and I feel and I see that the majority
of uh developers today that are using
agents they're using agents for smaller
tasks. They're still very supervisory.
So they're they're they're delegating
but they're delegating small
capabilities. They give very detailed
instructions of like write this piece.
They use it for things that are
immediately available or immediately
useful like learning some use of an API
or um you know just sort of building
things that are very repeatable. They
build small things with it.
>> What are your thoughts on adoption
through uh looking at organizations
costs of using models or tokens from
using models? Some people are more and
more doing that these days. Yeah,
there's a very controversial
view there, right, of whether you should
basically require people to spend more
[laughter] on the models. Um, I think
it's a very shortlived thing. So, I I do
see it today. People talk about how uh
that that measure is is like just a
means of driving adoption. Um, I think
everybody that says it has a bit of an
apology, you know, with it. Um, in part
because I think the models are actually
getting very expensive. And one of the
competencies of being good at using
agents is knowing when do you need to
use opus and when can use sonnet and
when can you use an open model you know
those are actually part of the sort of
the strength right and when do you give
the right instructions so the agent
doesn't need you know a thousand turns
to get it right but it can actually you
know get it get it done in one go and
and so there's actually an efficiency
element uh the metric that I like the
most and I think maybe has a shelf life
for a bit uh is the notion of merged
multiple requests. Uh and then some
people, Lemonade is a good example,
actually introduce the complexity
measure on top of the pull request. So
for starters, just
>> just kind of assess, you know, rate of
pull request merge rates, fine. Maybe
these are small pull requests, but as as
long as you kind of have established a
point in time and you're kind of seeing
the trend moving up, uh that is I think
a better measure for developers to say,
well, how many poll requests have you
open and how many were merged? And from
that point on, even if you cheated at
the beginning and you can kind of get to
like some small poll request because you
just started pushing things in that way,
you can only do that a little bit at the
beginning and then you still have to
accelerate that number over time. Uh so
I think that measure is probably a
slightly better one.
>> Mhm. So, so next up after thinking about
a potential future where you know 80%
plus in 2027 of of enterprise developers
and developers generally are going to be
using AI. Um we're going to switch to
biga uh in episode 69 talks about how AI
amplifies everything. Good engineering
practices bad engineering practices it
does them equally as well you know
whatever it sees. Let's hear from
>> Bakita
amplifies indiscriminately, right? So if
you have like a bad setup, you might
just amplify that bad setup, right? And
if you have a good one, everything might
go well, right? Can you actually in your
organization with your pipelines, with
your processes, can you support an
increase in throughput? I think a lot of
organizations are still underestimating
this foundation that you need.
>> Really interesting because it kind of
means, you know, you can't just put your
cowboy outfit on and just create
software. you still need to use good
practices. You need to guide and have
the right context to be able to get an
agent to do what you want the way you
want to do it. And that's really kind of
like the crux of what Bit is saying,
right?
>> Yeah, I agree. I I feel I really like
the idea of AI as a as a multiplier, an
amplifier of it. I it actually makes me
remember one of the early episodes we
had with with Dez uh from Intercom, one
of the co-founders of Intercom, who
talked even in the support world of
about garbage in, garbage out, right? or
you came in and if you were to say like
hey just replicate what's in you and
like learn from my knowledge base and
quickly you learn that well your
knowledge base has a whole bunch of
outdated stuff and kind of things that
are no longer correct. It's the same for
your codebase. If the agents just
replicate the codebase well a lot of the
things that you've done before in your
codebase you don't actually want to
repeat. So uh you you really have to be
uh mindful of uh of that. Um and so I I
think we we've kind of gone through that
phase a little bit in the AI world in
which the thinking was we will just
learn from your code
>> uh and we will replicate what
development and you don't actually hear
that uh much anymore. Um I think today
it is a lot more about context
engineering and about the definition of
what is the correct behavior to uh to
build out.
>> Uh and then you want to codify that and
you want to be consistent and first and
even if the agents are building things
from scratch then they might build it um
you might want them to be explicit about
the way and the decision that that
they've made as they've built it so that
future versions of that agent uh is able
to to build them out. So there's there's
more and more of of those types of like
definitions of what good looks like of
history of decisions you know of uh
building those out. I still think that
there's a a gap which makes sense just
with time around looping in the learning
into that of saying fine you've made
these decisions what would you see in
the deployed system that would make you
think well that decision was maybe not
very good or it's no longer correct can
I can I go and adapt so we still have to
evolve that
>> and also and also I guess what you need
to change as a result did that decision
come from context that needs to be
changed or is that a human decision that
needs to be changed
>> it's it's pulling feedback or data in
and understanding what was the root
cause of that issue.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I I agree. And actually,
it's interesting to think about also
making the migration to the change and
making that be incremental. You know, I
I saw a recent uh post from Intercom
about how they manage skills and all
that and they have a a test generator or
like something that tests their systems
as a as just sort of part of software
development. And when it finds a bug, it
looks for that pattern elsewhere in the
system and then it modifies it in those
areas as well. I don't know how
thoroughly and autonomously they do
that. But I think that type of pattern
has to be there. It has to be a sort of
self-healing, self-improving system. Um,
and it all comes back to that like the
whole SDLC, the end-to-end SDLC has to
be handled by the agents and what we
need is we need to really focus on what
correct behavior is and what are the
mechanisms and what are the things we
need to review versus can you know be
made autonomous around modifications to
that context and then how how does the
context meet the code when you modify
the context doing it and it's
interesting because people I think what
we're seeing today is like we're moving
so quickly but nobody has had
substantial mileage
with this yet. And so people haven't
experienced yet what happens when their
context goes stale. You know what
happens when you know like a practice
like we think today about make sure that
it applies the right practices but what
happens when a practice changes right
when a security issue changes. And so
that is that is very interesting
>> and also that the fact that we're never
going to be as manual as we are right
now with agents. Everything is, you
know, agents are getting better, but
we're also trusting them more. There's
going to be more autonomy than in future
than than than less.
>> Yeah. Great.
>> And and and in terms of that, we need,
you know, things to act correctly and we
need things to to to to be as we need
it. And and that's so so important
>> indeed.
>> Hey everyone, hope you're enjoying the
episode [music] so far. Our team is
working really hard behind the scenes to
bring you the best guests so we can have
the most informative conversations
[music] about Agentic development.
Whether that's talking about the latest
tools, the most efficient workflows, or
defining best practices. [music]
But for whatever reason, many of you
have yet to subscribe to the channel. If
you're enjoying the podcast and want us
to continue to bring you the very best
content, [music] please do us a favor
and hit that subscribe button. It really
does make a difference and lets us
continue to improve the quality of our
guests and build an even better product
for you. All right, back to the episode.
Okay, and then one of our actually one
of our many most popular episodes in
terms of uh in terms of the number
number of views was Olivia Pomel, Data
Dog CEO, who talked about uh the the
wonderful dream of no one waking up at
3:00 a.m. because of a critical
situation. Let's hear from Olivia. At
the end of the day, we think just
everybody will want automation,
>> right?
>> Every single company in the world will
want automation. That's the dream,
right? The dream is you never have to
wake up in the middle of the night ever
again to fix an issue. The issue has
been for you.
>> And so the bar for precision needs to be
very high on the on anything that has to
that relates to mobility.
And the good news is that I would say
three four years ago being completely
right about root cause most of the time
was science fiction and I think now it's
definitely within reach and we can
clearly see on the horizon the moment
where the this technology is good enough
to be put into the hands of customers on
in in a large amount large number of
situations.
>> What's the worst that can happen guy?
Yeah, I think you know we spoke a little
bit about root cause analysis and how
that is the sort of the dominant case
and I think it it just really lends
itself well to you have to sift through
a lot of data, you have to build those
and if you got it wrong then you've
wasted time as opposed to you've taken
out a system. Uh and so I think I think
those are useful and they have a little
bit of the coding assistant version over
there which is like surface candidates
for me right be an assistant for root
cause analysis now that technology is
improving to be able to uh to even like
get you good good inklings right of what
that is you know with context and so I
do think that this is you know we
touched on this already you know very
much the sort of the dream of not
getting woken up there's a there's a
nightmare version of this that we're
seeing and actually has manifested a lot
recently with all the supply chain
attacks which is uh what we're also
seeing is that attackers are becoming
increasingly agentic uh and there is a
marked rise in uh fishing attempts you
know that are scaling and are going
downstream and going into SMBs we're
seeing agents finding vulnerabilities in
open source libraries and so there was a
big push around uh a variety of supply
chain vulnerabilities supply chain
vulnerabilities are multiplied in in
different ways you know in part is
because attackers can find
vulnerabilities more easily uh and that
on top of that they can actually fish
like the Axios vulnerability that
happened right now had a fishing element
which sort of combines you know the
other capabilities of AI but then also
the agents are pulling in a lot of these
libraries and they're done with less
supervision so there's just this
trifecta of of of whatever multiffactor
you know of uh of uh of reasons that
drive it uh and so I think in in the in
the DevOps world as is often the case
right in the dev and devops world it's a
very positive message it's like you can
do this and we can all sing kumbaya
together and you know sleep well and
doing it because the systems will will
kind of be self-healing and we'll build
that and self-healing is is a DevOps
term right that has existed for a while.
In the security world there's a bit of a
you know if you don't then uh type of of
of risk scenario which is we have to
level up security handling to not just
find vulnerabilities but actually fix
them and then go all the way to deploy
to production and that forcing function
really again drives that sort of end to
end speed. What I like about it is that
it's actually a case in which you know
you really you should embrace full end
toend agentic capabilities so that you
are able to respond this quickly. So
again an extreme version of the the
DevOps kind of cloud move in which
initially it's like well it's insecure
to deploy multiple times uh a day or
whatever to have continuous deployment
and then it became well it is insecure
not to do that because the
vulnerabilities will happen the systems
do exist on it so the question is how
quickly can you respond and reach out
and so I think we'll see we'll see a lot
of that and I would expect this year to
be
>> security [clears throat] to be very much
at the forefront as agents are um are
being used for much more sort of real
production cases. Uh so you you'll see
both of those. You'll see the security
issues because agents were not used in
uh doing it like people were just sort
of slow attackers are becoming faster
than defenders
>> and there's a lot of understanding and
awareness of this in the security
industry but not real solutions yet. And
the second is you'll see security issues
because of of failures on the agent side
and unreliability. We've seen some leaks
from Enthropic, right? Whether it's clot
code that they've quickly clarified is a
human error. It's like it's the button
pusher human uh who's being, you know,
thrown under the bus. And we've seen
sort of the leak of of Mythos somewhat
ironic, you know, like super cyber
security model having a cyber security
leak on it. But there will be more and
more of those.
>> Yeah. And do you think, you know, for
the 3:00 a.m. kind of wake up, uh, do
you feel like that will turn more into a
human in the loop validation versus
actually, like you say, the important
piece is the activity, the action, the
root cause analysis, the fix, and
getting all of that done quick. Do you
still feel like there's, you know,
amount of time where we need human in
the loop to to build that trust or do
you feel people will
>> Yeah.
>> be more immediate in
>> I think really the the the best setup is
to make yourself error tolerant. And so
what you want is you want to have an
environment in which if the you let the
agent do it but you build the
infrastructure such that if the agent
has made the wrong decision it is
reversible. Uh and I think that's really
what we aspire. I increasingly think
about the mental model in which uh you
know if if you think there were some
things that were tolerated in waterfall
and were no longer tolerated in the
cloud era. Uh and the best teams in
waterfall were automating things or
finding issues early like shift left in
security is a good example of that
>> and then they were you know no longer
tolerated in cloud like you could not
get by without you know shifting
security left or by you know having
automated uh tests of some capacity on
because you just couldn't deal with the
speed. I think there's similarly now a
few things that are tolerated in the
cloud era and will be not tolerated in
the AI era largely due to speed. Uh and
many of them come down to the same
pattern of these were human actions,
human reviews that had to be done and
the best teams were automating these
things in the cloud era but you know in
the uh AI era the average team needs to
be doing that otherwise you just it
would not be viable for you to build in
this world. Let's switch gears a little
bit now to Matty Statashevki who is the
uh the the CEO and founder of 11 Labs.
He has some opinions on how we interact
with uh AI. Let's hear from Matty.
>> Like in general we think voice will be
the future of interactions, the digital
interactions of how you interact with
interfaces of of the digital world and
it can carry so much more emotion so
much understanding than text. So it it
will read your mind to an extent
[laughter]
but I know like you know maybe go to
Elon's kind of a neural link or some
scary options over there. Um yeah I mean
I think voice is definitely prevalent on
it. It's interesting because it's less
about just typing speed and more about
our human tendencies when we speak over
here. There's there's there's a you know
there's you know you know you know and
and all those
>> the audience don't know that that gets
edited out guy. So you know in our
automation technology makes that go away
and when you when you type something
then you bother fixing these things you
pause you think. So it it's actually not
just related to your time of sort of
typing down
>> it is a lot more uh kind of related to
how how much do you need to phrase how
much can you ramble on on it. And so
it's been really interesting to see how
voice and speech have become uh uh
common in the world of AI uh in in the
coding because coding requires that
precision. You know when you code you
can't you can't say you know you can
have an a you know in uh in that
interpretation but when you are
discussing things right and talking to
an agent then that's okay. the agent can
remove those things and they can take
that away and so it reduces the
cognitive load. It just allows you to to
ramble on. There's still value in
precision when you're instructing
something to the agent. But if context
is managed well, in this case it's
inline context. You ramble something,
the agent might create some instruction
files. That instruction file might be
the thing that you've passed to a sub
agent to implement things. Then it's
again if you use the human analogy a
little bit this is the sort of the
person the project manager right that
you are talking to and you can ramble on
to them and part of their job is to sort
of streamline your ramblings to uh to be
able to translate that into uh real
conversations. So it it's interesting I
think Mati is is right. It was clearly a
little bit self- serving to talk about
sort of voice uh being the future of it.
You know 11 Labs continues to sort of
shine and thrive and know since we've
had that episode. Interestingly, they've
actually expanded past audio and so now
they don't just do audio. Uh but uh I I
think I think you'll see more and more
of that text in the AI dev world as
well. You're seeing there's an
interesting pattern in cloud code and I
think it probably will be if not already
mimicked by others to delegate to use
sub agents a lot more. Mhm.
>> That to me is that analogy of the the
the the front agent that you have there
is the project manager and you're
interacting with it and then it will
delegate activity to sub agents to to do
the work. Um and I will say that just
like with project management, there's a
caveat about losing visibility. So when
you're in the terminal and you're giving
those instructions, it's a lot harder to
know what happens when you're when
you're making that delegation. So it's
interesting but I think generally
correct that voice will be uh
>> and of course I think Claude code
released a feature actually probably
nearly a month ago or so where if you
put there's a slash command now slashv
voice I think or something along those
lines where then it actually listens to
the mic and you can actually put uh from
your you know laptop and you can
actually just chat with claude code and
it feels quite natural actually for me I
quite I enjoy doing that naturally with
claude desktop actually anyway so it was
a natural addition for me so I'm
definitely in agreement. And it raises
the like there's a a very it's a very
different question to say will a thing
happen like what voice kind of be more
dominant than text and who would be the
players that win in that space. So it is
it is very interesting. I will say that
as we as we record this you know there's
been sort of recent updates on the cloud
side in which they've tightened up a lot
of where can claude be used and they
really want their harness. want their
interfaces. And so uh we're we're
probably starting to toy a little bit
with you know as companies get more
capable and entropic right now is in
that state do they seek to form more of
a closed garden around it and you know
hey you just need to use our systems and
run everything within our systems versus
the other trends where you see for
instance Nvidia committing to open code
and open claw and uh you know building
things that are very open and composable
system uh which once again feels a
little bit cloudesque a lot more web
like and we had in an early episode we
had uh Matt from Netlifi the co-founder
and CEO of Netifi talk about the
criticality of the open web and you know
how do we how do we build over there so
they've continued to invest in that as
sort of being a composable
infrastructure you know while you're
seeing you know Versell actually like
definitely uh supporting some elements
that are open but also mostly investing
in sort of the end-to-end experience and
making a very good end toend experience
within their kind of walled gardens,
right, of uh of it. So, it's it it's a
it's a just different questions. What
will happen and who will win or what
does it take to win are just very very
different questions at the pace that
this world moves.
>> Amazing. Well, look forward to chatting
about what's next in the in the next 100
episodes, but for now, that's all we
have time for. really fun to look back
and kind of like, you know, think about
some of the topics that were raised by
such amazing guests that we've had on
the podcast.
>> And I want to extend a huge thanks to to
all of you listeners who are uh really
kind of the reason that these guests,
you know, come on to sort of have these
conversations with us, right? And they
uh uh and just all the feedback that you
get and the suggestions for different
speakers and different guests uh that we
will have. So, thanks, keep on
listening, subscribe if you haven't uh
already on it. And if you have
suggestions for guests that we should
have in the next hundred episodes and
beyond on it, send them over. And of
course, you know, to all these amazing
guests that have sort of spent their
time sharing their learnings, their
perspectives, you know, with with us,
with you. Uh big thanks, very humbled,
very much enjoy the conversations,
learned from the conversations. And you
know at this pace uh a lot of the kind
of one of the critical elements of of
being able to deal with this space of
change is community is about sort of
learning together sharing perspectives
sharing these learnings. Um so we're
very uh grateful for you for sharing on
uh those uh those perspectives and we'll
continue to provide a stage uh for that
to happen.
>> Seconded. Well put. Thank you very much
for listening and tune in to the next
episode. Thanks guy.
>> Thank you.
Hey